welcome to meditating with John Rivera
no I teach and do academic and
scientific research on topics like
mindfulness related phenomena like
Insight flow this mystery motive during
its higher states of consciousness the
cultivation of wisdom in the aspiration
to enlightenment I've also been
practicing the positive meditation not a
contemplation in Tai Chi Chuan and Chi
kung for over 29 years and I've been
teaching and professionally for almost
20 years
welcome if you're here for the first
time you've course welcome to stay but
this is a progressive course every
Monday is a Dharma day and on that day I
teach some principles and practices that
build on previous principles and
practices in the description of this
video you'll find links to previous
lessons in previous six Tuesday's for
Friday we meet in and we said why
sometimes review how it was taught on
number day and then at the end of every
day Monday through Friday there's a Q&A
please direct any questions you might
have to this practice these sets of
practices as ecology practice that I'm
teaching you for broader questions
please join me on May 15th third Friday
of this month third Friday of every
month actually 3 p.m. est on the youth
drew live stream in which I answer those
broader type of questions now I need to
make an important announcement this
Monday the next is Dharma day we're
starting an hour later we're starting an
hour later due to a scheduling conflict
we're starting at 10:30 est next Monday
10:30 est okay so I'll make sure to send
out a reminder also on all the social
media platforms a couple general notes
I'm trying to do this as you know to
help as many people as possible is
challenging times if you could like this
video to raise its visibility on the
YouTube algorithm I'd be very very
helpful I would
very much appreciated so let's get ready
to sit please turn put your phones on do
not disturb
get your posture ready and we will begin
when I say you get begin
slowly begin to come out of your
practice trying as best you can to
integrate with your cultivated in your
practice with your everyday
consciousness and cognition perhaps by
reciting the five promises to yourself
okay we have some time for some
questions this is from Nevada truth when
directing Letta toward yourself should
be pictured to be picturing an image of
yourself for sensing yourself
I generally it's recommended that you
try sensing yourself and in particular
you try sensing this area this is sort
of the body armor area associated with
one's ego and center for some people
it's more here but this seems to be a
very good place you know because it's a
sort of our emotional center and things
like that at least where we embody it
so I recommend kind of sense yourself
especially this spot as opposed to just
relate to an image of yourself under a
Fed when trying to find my phone I
understand it as starting with following
the breath in the abdomen and expanding
the witness to chest and upper body
paying attention to all the body
sensations and trying to do the sick
Leslie isn't there a risk of my body's
you bullshitting me I imagine generating
those feelings and sensations am I
supposed to accept it as a as part of a
process that will go away well it could
be that your body is generating
sensations that are illusory but then
what you might want to do is ask what
standard you'd be applying against that
what is the standard you're using to say
well I think you know well what would
you use in order to realize that those
sensations are not actually being
generated by your body but just imagined
it's unclear what that would be I think
I think it's unclear like it's what
what's the difference at that level
between imagining and perception is it
when you're paying attention to your own
mind the very doubt that you're having
the thought that you're having are you
imagining that thought you're actually
having that thought you see when you're
getting down to those depths and this is
what the car decides to say
Machinery by which you're perceiving is
the machinery by which you're imagining
and we're getting into those depths
trying to find the clean line between
imagination perception I think I'm
concerned that it's a kind of false
precision it's not findable because of
the deep functional interpenetration so
I recommend going with the practice we
do have a standard of all just Rea
explain it the standard is auto and it's
a standard of transformative truths not
just a sense of conviction is your life
being transformed in a way that is
internalized abow into your practice and
is what's happening your practice
leading to transformation in your life
especially as noticed by other people
and if you could and you can stand back
and say what if all of thats an illusion
and then the problem with that is what
higher standard where where would you go
where would you be standing when you
were trying to make that evaluation it
seems to me that what we ultimately have
to fall back on is is our life as a
whole as comprehensively and coherently
as possible and that means both inner
and outer opening up are we feeling more
connected and is that reliably coherent
with our ability to make sense to make
connections to make friends etc and so
ultimately that's a kind of Buddhist
pragmatism I would say so I guess the
practical advice for you Andrea is if
you're experiencing that flow and it's
getting you into an absorbed embodied
awareness of your body it's like my
classes on my classes distorting my
vision yes but they distort my vision so
that I can actually see better my
undistorted vision is blurry and
confused mark lathis the use of bells
are Tibetan singing bowls etc and
meditation good bad indifferent tips I
have a singing bowl I used to use it
I didn't find I sort of let's make a pun
it's gonna say I didn't find that I
particularly resonated with the practice
I know that other people do I'm not
indifferent I did it just didn't sort of
catch up for me I enjoy making my
singing bowls ain't ringing a bell
before you meditate is very good
because it's that in the thing about a
bell especially in gongs right is you
have music as both inner and outer and
it spreads out as it moves in and then
it also slowly dissipates into emptiness
and if you follow it if you follow it
out and you follow it in and you follow
it right passing away gradually and
perceptibly into silence that can be
very conducive for getting you into a
mindful state so I recommend that if
you're able to do that and it works for
you that you should not continue making
use of it all right so just a few final
announcements I want to thank everybody
for joining today I want to remind
everybody Monday Dharma day 10:30 just
this one time 10:30 not 9:30 10:30 a.m.
est I want to thank my dear friend and
technomage amar my beloved son Jason
please subscribe to this channel to be
notified of the next video you'll also
find on that channel lots of videos and
my both voices wood for baekje and
awaking for the meeting crisis that
discuss and develop a lot of the topics
that are brought up in this course in
greater depth and also situate them in a
more encompassing wisdom framework
please invite others to this series I
think it can be helpful to people help
me help others if you're intending on
coming or even if you aren't but you
think it might be relevant to somebody
please invite people to come to the QA
next Monday the 15th at 3 p.m. est
reminder that we're doing this except
for next Monday which is at 10:00
we're doing this every weekday morning
at 9:30 a.m. est remember continuity of
practice more important than quantity
there is no enemy worse than your own
mind there is no ally no true friend
greater in your own mind thank you
everyone for your time and attention
I'll see you on Monday at 10:30